<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unchained Dev – Life</title>
    <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Unchained Dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 08:19:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://unchaineddev.github.io/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero1 Fest 2024</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/braindump/zero1-fest-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 08:19:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/braindump/zero1-fest-2024/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;center&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/braindump/zero1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;700px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last weekend I attended the Zero1 Fest &amp;ndash; the world’s first festival around
finance and money. It was exhilarating to be in the presence of people whose
content I deeply admire; whose profound knowledge especially in finance has
influenced and &amp;ldquo;de-influenced&amp;rdquo; me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the opportunity to see the Kamath brothers up close, whose startup serves
as a powerful reminder that a business can thrive without backing of venture
capital. I had a chat with Karthik Rangappa, curator of Varsity and expressed
deep appreciation for his captivating content. I was nostalgic to see Rob from
&amp;ldquo;M.A.D&amp;rdquo; fame, whose show was a beloved staple for 90s and early 2000s kids. I
had a brief moment with Prateek Singh, Founder &amp;amp; CEO of LearnApp and Zero1
Media, whose talk with Radhika Gupta (Edelweiss CEO) left a lasting impression.
Although I missed out on meeting many other familiar faces like Abid Hassan,
Rahul Subramanian, Nas, among others, I still had a wonderful time!&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Crooked Timber Of New India</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/new-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 20:40:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/new-india/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;I stumbled upon a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DLy3YOJeogA&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;YouTube video&lt;/a&gt;
featuring &lt;em&gt;Mr. Parakala Prabhakar&lt;/em&gt;, interviewed by few of the last esteemed
journalists left in our country today: &lt;em&gt;Mr. Karan Thapar&lt;/em&gt;. The discussion delved
into the current state of politics, economy and social fabric of our country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. &lt;em&gt;Parakala Prabhakar&lt;/em&gt; is a political activist, &lt;em&gt;economist&lt;/em&gt;, scholar, and
author. Parakala, if you are unaware, is also the husband of the current
Finance Minister, &lt;em&gt;Nirmala Sitharaman&lt;/em&gt;. This adds an intriguing level to this
discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parakala&amp;rsquo;s unapologetic honesty and unwavering stance against the Modi Regime
is profoundly shocking, yet not entirely unprecedented. It was really
compelling to see a man speak truths in a world of men and women intolerant of
criticism in any shape or form. My decision to to pick his book, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Crooked
Timber Of New India&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; was with a desire for a deeper understanding of our
polity, economy and progress as a nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his book, he speaks in length of the failures of the Modi Government,
particularly the false promises to reduce unemployment, abolish corruption,
demonetization of currency notes that broke the backbone of our economy,
mishandling of COVID-19, amongst others. In a chapter, Parakala skillfully
employs the &amp;ldquo;Rabbit-duck illusion&amp;rdquo; as an analogy to depict the state of affairs
within the ruling party. I found it very clever and insightful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mishandling of COVID-19 by the Central Government is unforgettable. It is marked
in history, as they conveniently prioritized their crony capitalists over
public good. The illusionary schemes were merely for show, nothing helped
citizens. Poverty was at an all-time high since 1990s. 75 Million were pushed
to poverty, and the government did nothing but praise itself for &amp;ldquo;2.5 Cr Jabs&amp;rdquo;.
Parakala shares one story of a young boy victim to the poverty of the New
India, and then shares a powerful quote by Gandhiji which made me feel hopeful
of a future leader that would bring about change like this &amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Whenever you are faced with a difficult situation, imagine the poorest of the
poor and see if your decision brings a smile to their faces.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another fascinating chapter was: &amp;ldquo;Egocracy: Digital Freedom and Data Privacy&amp;rdquo;.
Parakala deeply examines the rising internet shutdowns, concerning accumulation
of data from Big Tech Companies collected for government use, pervasive erosion
of privacy, content moderation, removing posts by targeting critics, and data
breaches. I was happy to read a well-researched and accurate account of the
state of privacy in India. It felt like a breath of fresh air to read this
essay, and I was glad to realize people like Parakala exist, to fight against
lost causes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of lost causes, there is a lot of horrible attempts to rewrite and
portray history. The fear of an incompetant leader swaying masses through media
and his oracy, calling his reign as &lt;em&gt;The New India&lt;/em&gt;, and what ever came before
him were all but an underwhelming effect says a lot about him. In addition, the
push for a singular national identity at the expense of democratic values is a
cause for deep concern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is lot of wistful politics at play, rather than focusing on pressing
issues. Obvious one is polarizing Hindu-Muslim dynamics, push for a singular
Hindu-Hindi identity for being hailed as truly Indian, population control of a
certain community by stoking fear about an imagined scenario of numerical
equality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading this book, you feel a void in your heart. Something you cannot
fill, something you cannot mend. The state of affairs in India today as
portrayed by Parakala makes your blood boil. Sadly, this is a harsh reality we
as citizens have conformed to. Yet, amidst the despair, the solution is a call
to action. Between we &lt;em&gt;as a people&lt;/em&gt; against governments who divide us by caste,
creed or religion. Against media houses who spread propaganda and cannot stand
criticism of the government. It is also a battle against the people amongst us
who undermine democracy and stay hidden behind an idelogy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letters From A Stoic</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/letters-from-a-stoic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 07:54:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/letters-from-a-stoic/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;This post contains letters from &lt;em&gt;Seneca&lt;/em&gt;, a Stoic philosopher of Ancient Rome,
and my thoughts on his philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Stoicism?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     Stoics identified the path to achieving it
[ good spirit ] with a life spent practicing the four virtues in everyday life:
&lt;br&gt;
     wisdom, courage, temperance or moderation, and
justice, and living in accordance with nature. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Letter II&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;letter-ii&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#letter-ii&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/book.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seneca&amp;rsquo;s second letter is addressed to Lucilius, emphasising significance of
settling one&amp;rsquo;s self and deriving joy from solitude. He advises against
consuming books from different authors, instead &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;focusing on authors whose
genius is unquestionable&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would slightly disagree with him on this point. There is no doubt genius
writers would have a great effect on one&amp;rsquo;s mind, however you cannot ignore the
impact of the human experience. If you are reading something not-so-genius but
you learn a valuable lesson from it, I would argue it would be a wise choice.
While Seneca&amp;rsquo;s analogy of a wound not healing if subjected to experiments of
several ointments, or a plant weakening from constant uprooting is compelling,
engaging with a multitude of viewpoints and getting perspective deepens your
understanding of things. With this in mind, I would not say reading a lot of
garbage self-help authors or a bunch of phony writers would do your life any
good. Picking the right authors is without a doubt a good first step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seneca also suggests focusing more on the quality than the quantity of books.
This resonates with my philosphy and it is something I really struggle with
sometimes. Whenever I start a book, my heart &lt;strong&gt;wants&lt;/strong&gt; to finish it (as most of
us would like to). However, this is a key point to keep in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;i&gt;To read that brings pleasure, and to let go of books that cause pain.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To use this knowledge as a shield against life&amp;rsquo;s adversities and cultivate the
habit of resilience is valuable advice. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t agree more with Seneca when
he says, &amp;ldquo;It is not the man who has too little who is poor, but the one who
hankers after more&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Letter III&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;letter-iii&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#letter-iii&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember the popular proverb, &lt;em&gt;A friend in need is a friend indeed&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this letter, Seneca addresses Lucilius&amp;rsquo;s distrust towards his friend, and
&lt;em&gt;dramatically&lt;/em&gt; questions him if he &amp;ldquo;actually&amp;rdquo; called him a friend or if it was
merely out of courtesy. This debate evokes a point in my life, when I stood by
this philosophy of &lt;em&gt;true friendship&lt;/em&gt;. (as ridiculous as it sounds) I reserved
the title of a &lt;em&gt;friend&lt;/em&gt; with those I shared a deep friendship, while others,
less intimately known, remained acquaintances. The significance of words may be
overlooked in today&amp;rsquo;s world, yet the value words hold must remain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/friends.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, &lt;em&gt;Friendship&lt;/em&gt; is a bond built on trust, where we willingly place our
hearts and souls at our friend&amp;rsquo;s feet, trusting they will not deceive us.
Overcoming fear of betrayal demands reflecting the same trust we have in
ourselves. Seneca offers timeless wisdom on this matter, advising against both
indiscriminately confiding in everyone and keeping secrets from our closest
friends. Certainly judgement must precede freely sharing thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seneca believes being busy in life doesn&amp;rsquo;t always equate to productivity,
rather signifies a troubled mind. Likewise, condemning all activity leads to
laziness and not a relaxed mind. He advocates for striking a balance and
suggests looking towards nature for relaxation. Below is a quote I really found
interesting in this letter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Some men have shrunk so far into dark corners that objects in broad daylight
seem quite blurred to them&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Letter V&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;letter-v&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#letter-v&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seneca earnestly approves of those constantly learning, determined for
self-improvement. To be a better man (or woman) is essential, however he warns
against doing it to seek attention, or for solely provoking others through
appearances or ways of living. This is profoundly accurate in an era, dominated
by FAANG mania, Instagram reelz and TikTok trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is fascinating how a philosopher born centuries ago accurately describes our
reality. Better yet shares his ideas on how to lead a simple life. Maybe, this
philosophy is deeply rooted in the essence of humanity, passed down through
generations; a promise of belonging to one race, one global community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seneca puts this beautifully: &lt;i&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our motto, as one knows, is to live in
conformity with nature.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some key points I found fascinating in this letter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admiring one&amp;rsquo;s way of life, and appreciate the beauty in its simplicity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admire one&amp;rsquo;s character and values, instead of their material possessions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seneca also highlights how &lt;em&gt;fear&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;hope&lt;/em&gt; march in unison &amp;ldquo;like a prisoner
and escort he is handcuffed to&amp;rdquo;. This theme is widely explored, so I would just
like to add how memory brings back the agony of fear, and as philosophical as
it sounds, one must live in the present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Letter VI&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;letter-vi&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#letter-vi&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this letter, Seneca writes to Lucilius that he observes not only
improvement, but also transformation within himself. While humbly admitting his
imperfections, Seneca admits the significance of sharing his feelings with his
friend (as discussed in a previous letter). Additionally, he highlights the
mutual benefit of exchanging insights through shared books. Knowledge is
valuable if shared, useless if held in secret. My philosophy on this remains.
Talking to someone each day and studying their character benefits more than
conversing with someone rarely. More often than not, to be your own friend too
is a wonderful idea of progress, atleast in theory. Nonetheless to share-it-all
with a friend is a priceless benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stoicism&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stoicism&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bangalore Weather is Changing</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/bangalore-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 05:21:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/bangalore-weather/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;center&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/bangalore.jpg&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bengaluru is like a dear friend who gets along really well with anyone. She&amp;rsquo;s
known for her pleasant nature, creative mind, love for greens and hanging out
with people of diverse backgrounds. As someone who has lived with Bengaluru,
like many of us, who deeply value the essence of her character, I would reject
the idea if someone told me our beloved city could a face water crisis or reach
a scorching high temperature of 37 degrees this summer. (again)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all, we love her as we have seen her &amp;ndash; Grow as a quaint garden city to a
beautiful bustling metropolis. A city crowded by cars and cafes, ignoring the
effects of climate change and urbanization. And now our dear friend is weary. While
her heart beats with a passion for technology and innovation, she longs for a
break from endless development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ensure her sustainability for years to come, let us recognize her need to
prioritize self-care. Here are a few simple things you can do to nurture your
friendsip with Bengaluru.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conserve water by fixing leaks, taking shorter showers, turning off taps when not in use, and using water wisely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn off lights, fans, and electronic devices when not in use to conserve energy and lower utility bills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advocate for increased tree planting initiatives, and protest against cutting down trees for corporate profit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice proper waste management by segregating waste at the source into recyclables and non-recyclables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Opt for public transport whenever possible to alleviate carbon emissions and traffic congestion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spread awareness about environmental issues and the importance of sustainability through social media and other mediums.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Empire of Hell</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/empire-of-hell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 07:32:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/empire-of-hell/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;All the world&amp;rsquo;s a digital stage, &lt;br&gt;
and all the men and women merely scrollin&amp;rsquo; &amp;ndash; &lt;br&gt;
with no exits, their entrance is a screen &amp;ndash; &lt;br&gt;
a portal to their unseen dreams. broken&lt;br&gt;
and broke. impulse and hope-less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a double-edged sword. swallow whole&lt;br&gt;
pleasure and pain. one man at their time&lt;br&gt;
plays many parts of ruin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His acts being seven gigs of your intimate data.&lt;br&gt;
first phase of his playbook &amp;ndash; lure you in.&lt;br&gt;
Then gather and sell, finally build networth&lt;br&gt;
and tell the world, &amp;ldquo;I created an empire of hell.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>first blog</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/firstblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 21:46:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/firstblog/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;in the vast expanse of the internet, i have constructed a small place of my own &amp;ndash; a webpage, with a philosophy of its own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so if you don&amp;rsquo;t know me, let me tell you, i like simple stuff. and strangely enough i chose not to make this site super responsive with a shit-load of javascript. oh yes, if you have not guessed it already, i used a static site generator for this page. to be precise, &lt;em&gt;hugo&lt;/em&gt;. with a minimal theme under the hood and an elegant design, i am sure you might be really impressed by the responsiveness and the speed of my page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but you might be wondering why a webpage? i am going to tell you even if you are not wondering though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in all honesty, i wanted to have a place of my own on the internet: to have the freedom to put whatever i want in one place,
rather than scattering it all around social media accounts.
i can share this one link with anyone and BOOM! access to everything i post. sounds kind of like linktree, which sounds like a great idea if you are lazy to make a simple html page. hehe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i also don&amp;rsquo;t like the idea of getting into social media again, so this would be my ideal place, where random people can find my site and admire the simplicity of it, and of course know me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so if you want to subscribe to my rss or would like to keep visiting my webpage, here are a few things i will &lt;strong&gt;write about&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cinema&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;technology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;literature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;anything about life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;new stuff i learned&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;philosophy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sports (cricket, maybe)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an endless list of links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i have been wanting to do this for about a year now and here we are!
&lt;br&gt;
i like my hecking site and i hope you do too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if you find any issues with
my site, you can submit it &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/unchaineddev/unchaineddev.github.io/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/contact&#34; &gt;me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
