<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unchained Dev – Life</title>
    <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Unchained Dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 05:21:33 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://unchaineddev.github.io/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bangalore Weather is Changing</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/bangalore-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 05:21:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/bangalore-weather/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;center&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/bangalore.jpg&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bengaluru is like a dear friend who gets along really well with anyone. She&amp;rsquo;s
known for her pleasant nature, creative mind, love for greens and hanging out
with people of diverse backgrounds. As someone who has lived with Bengaluru,
like many of us, who deeply value the essence of her character, I would reject
the idea if someone told me our beloved city could a face water crisis or reach
a scorching high temperature of 37 degrees this summer. (again)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all, we love her as we have seen her &amp;ndash; Grow as a quaint garden city to a
beautiful bustling metropolis. A city crowded by cars and cafes, ignoring the
effects of climate change and urbanization. And now our dear friend is weary. While
her heart beats with a passion for technology and innovation, she longs for a
break from endless development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ensure her sustainability for years to come, let us recognize her need to
prioritize self-care. Here are a few simple things you can do to nurture your
friendsip with Bengaluru.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conserve water by fixing leaks, taking shorter showers, turning off taps when not in use, and using water wisely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn off lights, fans, and electronic devices when not in use to conserve energy and lower utility bills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advocate for increased tree planting initiatives, and protest against cutting down trees for corporate profit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice proper waste management by segregating waste at the source into recyclables and non-recyclables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Opt for public transport whenever possible to alleviate carbon emissions and traffic congestion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spread awareness about environmental issues and the importance of sustainability through social media and other mediums.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Empire of Hell</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/empire-of-hell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 07:32:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/empire-of-hell/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;All the world&amp;rsquo;s a digital stage, &lt;br&gt;
and all the men and women merely scrollin&amp;rsquo; &amp;ndash; &lt;br&gt;
with no exits, their entrance is a screen &amp;ndash; &lt;br&gt;
a portal to their unseen dreams. broken&lt;br&gt;
and broke. impulse and hope-less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a double-edged sword. swallow whole&lt;br&gt;
pleasure and pain. one man at their time&lt;br&gt;
plays many parts of ruin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His acts being seven gigs of your intimate data.&lt;br&gt;
first phase of his playbook &amp;ndash; lure you in.&lt;br&gt;
Then gather and sell, finally build networth&lt;br&gt;
and tell the world, &amp;ldquo;I created an empire of hell.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>first blog</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/firstblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 21:46:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/firstblog/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;in the vast expanse of the internet, i have constructed a small place of my own &amp;ndash; a webpage, with a philosophy of its own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so if you don&amp;rsquo;t know me, let me tell you, i like simple stuff. and strangely enough i chose not to make this site super responsive with a shit-load of javascript. oh yes, if you have not guessed it already, i used a static site generator for this page. to be precise, &lt;em&gt;hugo&lt;/em&gt;. with a minimal theme under the hood and an elegant design, i am sure you might be really impressed by the responsiveness and the speed of my page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but you might be wondering why a webpage? i am going to tell you even if you are not wondering though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in all honesty, i wanted to have a place of my own on the internet: to have the freedom to put whatever i want in one place,
rather than scattering it all around social media accounts.
i can share this one link with anyone and BOOM! access to everything i post. sounds kind of like linktree, which sounds like a great idea if you are lazy to make a simple html page. hehe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i also don&amp;rsquo;t like the idea of getting into social media again, so this would be my ideal place, where random people can find my site and admire the simplicity of it, and of course know me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so if you want to subscribe to my rss or would like to keep visiting my webpage, here are a few things i will &lt;strong&gt;write about&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cinema&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;technology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;literature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;anything about life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;new stuff i learned&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;philosophy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sports (cricket, maybe)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an endless list of links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i have been wanting to do this for about a year now and here we are!
&lt;br&gt;
i like my hecking site and i hope you do too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if you find any issues with
my site, you can submit it &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/unchaineddev/unchaineddev.github.io/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/contact&#34; &gt;me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
