<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unchained Dev – Privacy</title>
    <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/tags/privacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Privacy on Unchained Dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 07:12:53 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://unchaineddev.github.io/tags/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Pictures</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/keeping-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 07:12:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/keeping-pictures/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;For as long as I can remember, I hated the idea of keeping old pictures. I have
always found myself deleting them like bad memories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a world where marketing and physical appearance reign supreme, I shied away
from keeping pictures in my adolescent years. My insecurities often kept me
from embracing moments, making me uncomfortable whenever someone wanted to take
a picture with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe this worsened from the profound impact of social media in my life.
With great severity, big tech companies were aggressively pushing their apps on
our faces during that period. It was truly overwhelming. Falling victim to such
a phenomenon feels more or less being enslaved. Facebook, Instagram, Snapchat,
Twitter: these are apps which you do not really need in your day-to-day life. I
have come to realize they thrive on your insecurities. Nonetheless, I digress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had this unusual philosophy about pictures. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure where I picked it
from — maybe something I read or heard, I don&amp;rsquo;t know. I can be a bit
philosophical &lt;del&gt;sometimes&lt;/del&gt;, you know. The idea centered around &lt;em&gt;complete focus
on the moment itself, rather than documenting it&lt;/em&gt;. Extending to this idea,
there was another that suggested &lt;em&gt;great memories are those deeply etched in
your mind, something you can look back on and feel, rather than just see in the
form of media.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funny thing as I write this and reflect on the past few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed a
strange habit: I find myself meticulously organizing my pictures in different
folders.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>xz has a secret backdoor</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/xz-backdoor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 05:20:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/xz-backdoor/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;I already made a blog post on &lt;a href=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/archiving-files-using-tar/&#34; &gt;archiving files using
tar&lt;/a&gt; that covered gzip, a utility tool
to archive files with compression. In the same way, xz utils is an open-source
lossless data compression tool primarily focused on the &lt;strong&gt;.xz&lt;/strong&gt; file format,
suitable for archiving large amount of data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately xz has been a victim to a highly sophisticated attack aimed at
injecting a secret backdoor, that resulted in compromise of numerous
distributions such as Debian, Kali, and openSUSE. This attack gave malicious
actors Remote Code Execution (RCE) privileges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily though, a Microsoft engineer Andres Freund discovered this issue by pure luck and
reported the issue when malicious code was found in a tar ball of liblzma (a library to implement compression).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The malicious actor who signed the tarball was a long-standing contributor to
the project, who had built trust for years. While the original maintainer was
inactive in the project, this bad actor by the name &amp;ldquo;Jia Tan&amp;rdquo; earned the
community&amp;rsquo;s confidence through their positive contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This serves as a reminder to always do your due diligence,as &lt;em&gt;with great power
comes great responsibility.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Intercepts Web Traffic</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/fb-intercepts-web-traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 12:47:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/fb-intercepts-web-traffic/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;In a newly disclosed court document,&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; it was revealed that Facebook launched
a secretive initiative called GhostBusters in the late 2010s, which could
intercept and decrypt the network traffic between people using Snapchat’s app
and its servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This enabled them to maintain a competitive advantage over other platforms,
primarily Snapchat, later followed with Youtube and Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How did they do this?&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;how-did-they-do-this&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#how-did-they-do-this&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In early 2010s, Facebook acquired Onavo, an Israeli-based VPN service and
mobile data analytics company known for data compression technology. This
innovative technology was used to mitigate high bandwidth usage due to the high
mobile data costs at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the acquision of this company, they integrated an advert on Facebook
called &amp;ldquo;protect&amp;rdquo;, which redirected users to download Onavo. Once this was
enabled, Facebook could easily track any application you use on your phone and
gather insightful data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What now?&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;what-now&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#what-now&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you use any meta products, which sadly is the case nowadays, try to isolate
your environment. By isolating your browsing activities, you can better protect
your personal information and reduce the likelihood of being tracked or
targeted by malicious actors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://techcrunch.com/2024/03/26/facebook-secret-project-snooped-snapchat-user-traffic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://techcrunch.com/2024/03/26/facebook-secret-project-snooped-snapchat-user-traffic/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signal Gets Usernames!</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/braindump/signal-gets-usernames/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 11:05:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/braindump/signal-gets-usernames/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Signal is a great messaging app for private digital communications. Features like end-to-end encryption,
privacy and security is time-tested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the introduction to usernames, exposure to phone numbers is minimal. It is a great feature
to have when you do not want to share your number with someone for a chat. The phone number is used
for sign up, however it will no longer be visible to everyone on Signal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is wonderful news for privacy and security enthusiasts, journalists, whistleblowers, and a big win
for digital freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/braindump/signal&#34; width=&#34;400px&#34;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
