<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unchained Dev – film</title>
    <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/tags/film/</link>
    <description>Recent content in film on Unchained Dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 19:27:10 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://unchaineddev.github.io/tags/film/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>jawan - a review</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/jawan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 19:27:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/jawan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;last thursday, i went to watch the socio-political action thriller, &amp;ldquo;Jawan&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;there were two compelling reasons i couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford to miss this film: first, my unwavering admiration for the superstar &lt;em&gt;Shah Rukh Khan&lt;/em&gt;, and second, my curiosity about the unique mummified look that had been teased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/jawan.png&#34; width=&#34;400px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;apart from this, there was the film&amp;rsquo;s antagonist played by our very own &lt;em&gt;Makkal Selvan&lt;/em&gt;, whose outstanding portrayal of &amp;ldquo;Michael Vedanayagam&amp;rdquo; in the web series &lt;em&gt;Farzi&lt;/em&gt; had left a lasting impression on me. his performance was a delightful blend of ruthlessness, humor, and sheer entertainment in the show. it was evident that he brought the same brutality in jawan. lastly, of course, &lt;em&gt;Nayanthara&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Deepika&lt;/em&gt;, whose brief appearance had a significant impact in the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;talking of the story &amp;ndash; i knew since the moment i stepped in, it would have Atlee&amp;rsquo;s trademark style &amp;ndash; a dramatic narrative with a strong social message and a hallmark of masala films &amp;ndash; when the hero is in danger, call the hero himself to save the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;what is memorable about jawan though, is the opening sequence. Atlee skillfully packages the stardom of SRK, and lets us have a seat for the grand and dramatic face reveal. a few glimpses doesn&amp;rsquo;t cut it, oh no, it has to be extravagant. is it realistic, heck no, but was it exciting and undeniably cool, HELL YEAH! it was one of those moments you cannot get your eyes out of. it leaves you spellbound even though you know what&amp;rsquo;s coming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;speaking of SRK, he is the villianous, bald, mysterious vigilante. he is also a super cool jawan, with a moustache to die for. and in the second half with slick action sequences in his wolverine-like appearance, it was nothing short of paisa wasool entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;another reason not to miss this film is &lt;em&gt;Anirudh&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt; music. he delivers cinematic bangers at this point. while the songs were mediocre at best, the background score packs a punch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if you like indian films or not, one thing is for sure though, this film would make your heart go &lt;em&gt;maasi, maasi, maasi, maasi, maasi, maasi, maasi&lt;/em&gt; ..&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
