<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unchained Dev – Film</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/film/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Film on Unchained Dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 07:13:55 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/film/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>12th Fail</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/12th-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 07:13:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/12th-fail/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;center&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/12th-fail.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not your typical underdog story where the protagonist goes from poverty to prosperity. 12th fail is an inspiring take on hope, determination, honesty and failure. Contrary to many other bollywood biographies, lack of a traditional villain in this story is a bold move. This made it all the more intriguing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover VVC captures the universal struggle of truth and empathy, creating a narrative that resonates deeply with the audience and effortlessly brings tears to the surface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vikrant Massey&amp;rsquo;s performance in this film is nothing short of extraordinary. His role as &lt;em&gt;Manoj&lt;/em&gt; is deserving of a National Award. The supporting cast were equally remarkable in their roles that contributed to the film&amp;rsquo;s excellence. What stood out to me most was the beautiful score composed by Shantanu Moitra, which served as the soulful essence of the film. It added more depth to the narrative and made it a good cinematic experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In its entirety, &amp;lsquo;12th Fail&amp;rsquo; emerges as a thought-provoking masterpiece. Beyond mere entertainment, it is inspiring. It is one of those films that one can revisit for a much-needed restart during moments of demotivation.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Films - 2023</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/best-films-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 20:05:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/best-films-2023/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;these are my favorite films of 2023. of course, there are better films i have missed. do let me know if any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;English/Foreign&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;englishforeign&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#englishforeign&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barbenheimer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Barbenheimer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two films that are a phenomenon in itself - Greta Gerwig&amp;rsquo;s hysterical comedy and Nolan&amp;rsquo;s Atomic Bomb. My favorites this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Killers_of_the_Flower_Moon_%28film%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Killers Of The Flower Moon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An epic about Osage killings. Killers Of The Flower Moon is a good Western with fine storytelling; the kind you expect from a Scorcese film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Past_Lives_%28film%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Past Lives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Past lives takes a very nuanced approach to the what-ifs. it is praiseworthy for its spectacular dialogue and emotional story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Killer_%282023_film%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Killer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael Fassbender, &amp;ldquo;the Killer&amp;rdquo; assassin on a killing spree after a hit goes wrong. Yikes, truly worth a watch!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Are_You_There_God%3F_It%27s_Me,_Margaret._%28film%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Are you there God? It&amp;rsquo;s me, Margaret.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A coming-of-age drama which I did not expect I would like. It&amp;rsquo;s a simple story of a young girl and the challenges she faces in her adolescence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Suzume&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Suzume&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A beautiful world of Shinkai through a fantastical adventure of Suzume, helping a mysterious man close doors that is causing disasters in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Haunting_in_Venice&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;A Haunting in Venice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet another Poirot story you just cannot get enough of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anatomy_of_a_Fall&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Anatomy Of A Fall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A courtroom drama about a writer trying to prove her innocence in her husband&amp;rsquo;s death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BlackBerry_%28film%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Blackberry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;honestly after watching this film, it just makes you want to turn back time.. and own a &lt;em&gt;blackberry&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mission:_Impossible_%E2%80%93_Dead_Reckoning_Part_One&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Mission Impossible: Dead Reckoning Part One&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine an omnipotent A.I taking over the world? Well, this movie could potentially be the trailer of what&amp;rsquo;s to happen irl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knock_at_the_Cabin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Knock At the Cabin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knock, Knock, who&amp;rsquo;s there? A prophecy, delivered by four individuals who claim the fate of the world hinges on sacrificing a family member.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Indian films&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;indian-films&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#indian-films&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;em&gt;This year was the year of commercial cinema&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/12th_Fail&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;12th Fail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An extraordinary take on the real-life story of Manoj Kumar Sharma, who overcame extreme poverty to become an Indian Police Service officer. It&amp;rsquo;s my favorite Indian film this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sirf_Ek_Bandaa_Kaafi_Hai&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sirf Ek Banda Kaafi Hai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another courtroom drama I liked with a delicate subject starring Bajpayee, who time and again proves, &lt;em&gt;ki ek acchi film ke liye sirf ek banda kaafi hai.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pathaan_%28film%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Pathaan&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jawan_%28film%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jawan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s just say Pathaan is an event film, while Jawan is a longing for Shah Rukh Khan to be back on screen again. Purely commercial entertainers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Animal_%282023_film%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Animal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is the hype real? Well, from a technical standpoint it is good, it is bold &amp;amp; unlike any other Indian film you will see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maamannan&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Maamannan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A politically charged drama with beautiful imagery and unique metaphors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jailer_%282023_Tamil_film%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jailer&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leo_%282023_Indian_film%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Leo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big commercial stars with over-the-top action set-pieces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ponniyin_Selvan:_II&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ponniyin Selvan - Part II&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS-2 fares well in terms of filmmaking in comparsion to the first part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2018_%28film%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kannur_Squad&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kannur Squad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both stories have a common theme of taking charge as a leader, working with a team and driven by human emotions.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jawan - a review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/jawan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 19:27:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/jawan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;last thursday, i went to watch the socio-political action thriller, &amp;ldquo;Jawan&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;there were two compelling reasons i couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford to miss this film: first, my unwavering admiration for the superstar &lt;em&gt;Shah Rukh Khan&lt;/em&gt;, and second, my curiosity about the unique mummified look that had been teased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/jawan.png&#34; width=&#34;400px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;apart from this, there was the film&amp;rsquo;s antagonist played by our very own &lt;em&gt;Makkal Selvan&lt;/em&gt;, whose outstanding portrayal of &amp;ldquo;Michael Vedanayagam&amp;rdquo; in the web series &lt;em&gt;Farzi&lt;/em&gt; had left a lasting impression on me. his performance was a delightful blend of ruthlessness, humor, and sheer entertainment in the show. it was evident that he brought the same brutality in jawan. lastly, of course, &lt;em&gt;Nayanthara&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Deepika&lt;/em&gt;, whose brief appearance had a significant impact in the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;talking of the story &amp;ndash; i knew since the moment i stepped in, it would have Atlee&amp;rsquo;s trademark style &amp;ndash; a dramatic narrative with a strong social message and a hallmark of masala films &amp;ndash; when the hero is in danger, call the hero himself to save the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;what is memorable about jawan though, is the opening sequence. Atlee skillfully packages the stardom of SRK, and lets us have a seat for the grand and dramatic face reveal. a few glimpses doesn&amp;rsquo;t cut it, oh no, it has to be extravagant. is it realistic, heck no, but was it exciting and undeniably cool, HELL YEAH! it was one of those moments you cannot get your eyes out of. it leaves you spellbound even though you know what&amp;rsquo;s coming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;speaking of SRK, he is the villianous, bald, mysterious vigilante. he is also a super cool jawan, with a moustache to die for. and in the second half with slick action sequences in his wolverine-like appearance, it was nothing short of paisa wasool entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;another reason not to miss this film is &lt;em&gt;Anirudh&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt; music. he delivers cinematic bangers at this point. while the songs were mediocre at best, the background score packs a punch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if you like indian films or not, one thing is for sure though, this film would make your heart go &lt;em&gt;maasi, maasi, maasi, maasi, maasi, maasi, maasi&lt;/em&gt; ..&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
