<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unchained Dev – Lifestyle</title>
    <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/tags/lifestyle/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lifestyle on Unchained Dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 11:58:39 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://unchaineddev.github.io/tags/lifestyle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Coffee Can Investing - A Review</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/coffee-can-investing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 11:58:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/coffee-can-investing/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;The best time to plant a tree was twenty years ago; the second best time is now.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I strongly beleive in the eight wonder of the world. It may be common sensical
for someone with good discipline, patience, and consistency that the secret
lies in waiting for the magic to unfold. The only way, my friend is paying the
price: &lt;em&gt;Time&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This magical reminder comes in a form of a book: Coffee Can Investing by Saurab
Mukherjea and his team, that have created a roadmap that captures the common
pitfalls of a common retail investor. A guide to make wise financial decisions
without compromising on your wants and desires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would highly recommend this book to someone who wants to filter out the noise
and focus on the goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Note:&lt;/u&gt; It may not be necessary for everyone to read the entire book, yet
skimming through to understand the core philosophy should do the trick.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bangalore Weather is Changing</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/bangalore-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 05:21:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/bangalore-weather/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;center&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/bangalore.jpg&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bengaluru is like a dear friend who gets along really well with anyone. She&amp;rsquo;s
known for her pleasant nature, creative mind, love for greens and hanging out
with people of diverse backgrounds. As someone who has lived with Bengaluru,
like many of us, who deeply value the essence of her character, I would reject
the idea if someone told me our beloved city could a face water crisis or reach
a scorching high temperature of 37 degrees this summer. (again)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all, we love her as we have seen her &amp;ndash; Grow as a quaint garden city to a
beautiful bustling metropolis. A city crowded by cars and cafes, ignoring the
effects of climate change and urbanization. And now our dear friend is weary. While
her heart beats with a passion for technology and innovation, she longs for a
break from endless development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ensure her sustainability for years to come, let us recognize her need to
prioritize self-care. Here are a few simple things you can do to nurture your
friendsip with Bengaluru.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conserve water by fixing leaks, taking shorter showers, turning off taps when not in use, and using water wisely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn off lights, fans, and electronic devices when not in use to conserve energy and lower utility bills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advocate for increased tree planting initiatives, and protest against cutting down trees for corporate profit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice proper waste management by segregating waste at the source into recyclables and non-recyclables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Opt for public transport whenever possible to alleviate carbon emissions and traffic congestion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spread awareness about environmental issues and the importance of sustainability through social media and other mediums.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Empire of Hell</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/empire-of-hell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 07:32:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/empire-of-hell/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;All the world&amp;rsquo;s a digital stage, &lt;br&gt;
and all the men and women merely scrollin&amp;rsquo; &amp;ndash; &lt;br&gt;
with no exits, their entrance is a screen &amp;ndash; &lt;br&gt;
a portal to their unseen dreams. broken&lt;br&gt;
and broke. impulse and hope-less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a double-edged sword. swallow whole&lt;br&gt;
pleasure and pain. one man at their time&lt;br&gt;
plays many parts of ruin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His acts being seven gigs of your intimate data.&lt;br&gt;
first phase of his playbook &amp;ndash; lure you in.&lt;br&gt;
Then gather and sell, finally build networth&lt;br&gt;
and tell the world, &amp;ldquo;I created an empire of hell.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>70 Hours per Week</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/70-hours-per-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 06:02:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/70-hours-per-week/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Infosys&lt;/em&gt; founder Narayana Murthy recently said that, young Indians must work 70 hours a week. &amp;ndash; a phenomenal recommendation from a prominent capitalist. I respect his achievements but a statement like this makes me want to question his intelligence or, take any of these wise old men seriously. His idea is if you want India to realize its economic potential every young Indian must say: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;This is my country. I want to work 70 hours a week.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt; 
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/modern-slave.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
 
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, you do not need to work 70 hours to realize its economic potential.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Maybe he forgot the part where the quality of life also plays a crucial part in economic development? Maybe higher wages would help? I don&amp;rsquo;t know, I am no expert. Nonetheless for the sake of argument, let&amp;rsquo;s explore the numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming a five-day work week, and subtracting 70 hours for work leaves out 50 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we allocate a bare minimum portion for essential activities like sleeping (averaging 8 hours a day) and meals (1.5 hours a day for three meals), we are left with barely a dozen hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have not included commuting, grooming or leisure time for that matter. it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to acknowledge that quality of life plays a significant role in economic development, which Murthy happily chose to ignore in his statement. Merely advocating for longer work hours without addressing other factors undermines overall well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and the nationalist angle is ridiculous. for the sake of India, you cannot work 14 hours a day? Oh come on?! Where&amp;rsquo;s all the energy draining? Don&amp;rsquo;t you tell me you are working two jobs?? Oh right, that&amp;rsquo;s called moonlighting. &lt;em&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t do that&lt;/em&gt;, that&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/tech/information-tech/infosys-warns-employees-on-moonlighting-says-could-lead-to-termination/articleshow/94169072.cms&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;unethical&lt;/a&gt;! You can only slog for us, because we are a big company and
you are our &lt;em&gt;modern slave&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.businessinsider.in/policy/economy/news/billionaire-businessman-says-young-indians-should-work-70-hours-a-week/articleshow/104787562.cms&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.businessinsider.in/policy/economy/news/billionaire-businessman-says-young-indians-should-work-70-hours-a-week/articleshow/104787562.cms&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.investopedia.com/ask/answers/032415/what-are-some-ways-economic-growth-can-be-achieved.asp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.investopedia.com/ask/answers/032415/what-are-some-ways-economic-growth-can-be-achieved.asp&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
