<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unchained Dev – Lifestyle</title>
    <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/tags/lifestyle/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lifestyle on Unchained Dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 07:54:08 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://unchaineddev.github.io/tags/lifestyle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Letters From A Stoic</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/letters-from-a-stoic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 07:54:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/letters-from-a-stoic/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;This post contains letters from &lt;em&gt;Seneca&lt;/em&gt;, a Stoic philosopher of Ancient Rome,
and my thoughts on his philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Stoicism?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     Stoics identified the path to achieving it
[ good spirit ] with a life spent practicing the four virtues in everyday life:
&lt;br&gt;
     wisdom, courage, temperance or moderation, and
justice, and living in accordance with nature. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Letter II&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;letter-ii&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#letter-ii&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/book.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seneca&amp;rsquo;s second letter is addressed to Lucilius, emphasising significance of
settling one&amp;rsquo;s self and deriving joy from solitude. He advises against
consuming books from different authors, instead &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;focusing on authors whose
genius is unquestionable&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would slightly disagree with him on this point. There is no doubt genius
writers would have a great effect on one&amp;rsquo;s mind, however you cannot ignore the
impact of the human experience. If you are reading something not-so-genius but
you learn a valuable lesson from it, I would argue it would be a wise choice.
While Seneca&amp;rsquo;s analogy of a wound not healing if subjected to experiments of
several ointments, or a plant weakening from constant uprooting is compelling,
engaging with a multitude of viewpoints and getting perspective deepens your
understanding of things. With this in mind, I would not say reading a lot of
garbage self-help authors or a bunch of phony writers would do your life any
good. Picking the right authors is without a doubt a good first step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seneca also suggests focusing more on the quality than the quantity of books.
This resonates with my philosphy and it is something I really struggle with
sometimes. Whenever I start a book, my heart &lt;strong&gt;wants&lt;/strong&gt; to finish it (as most of
us would like to). However, this is a key point to keep in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;i&gt;To read that brings pleasure, and to let go of books that cause pain.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To use this knowledge as a shield against life&amp;rsquo;s adversities and cultivate the
habit of resilience is valuable advice. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t agree more with Seneca when
he says, &amp;ldquo;It is not the man who has too little who is poor, but the one who
hankers after more&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Letter III&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;letter-iii&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#letter-iii&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember the popular proverb, &lt;em&gt;A friend in need is a friend indeed&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this letter, Seneca addresses Lucilius&amp;rsquo;s distrust towards his friend, and
&lt;em&gt;dramatically&lt;/em&gt; questions him if he &amp;ldquo;actually&amp;rdquo; called him a friend or if it was
merely out of courtesy. This debate evokes a point in my life, when I stood by
this philosophy of &lt;em&gt;true friendship&lt;/em&gt;. (as ridiculous as it sounds) I reserved
the title of a &lt;em&gt;friend&lt;/em&gt; with those I shared a deep friendship, while others,
less intimately known, remained acquaintances. The significance of words may be
overlooked in today&amp;rsquo;s world, yet the value words hold must remain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/friends.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, &lt;em&gt;Friendship&lt;/em&gt; is a bond built on trust, where we willingly place our
hearts and souls at our friend&amp;rsquo;s feet, trusting they will not deceive us.
Overcoming fear of betrayal demands reflecting the same trust we have in
ourselves. Seneca offers timeless wisdom on this matter, advising against both
indiscriminately confiding in everyone and keeping secrets from our closest
friends. Certainly judgement must precede freely sharing thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seneca believes being busy in life doesn&amp;rsquo;t always equate to productivity,
rather signifies a troubled mind. Likewise, condemning all activity leads to
laziness and not a relaxed mind. He advocates for striking a balance and
suggests looking towards nature for relaxation. Below is a quote I really found
interesting in this letter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Some men have shrunk so far into dark corners that objects in broad daylight
seem quite blurred to them&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Letter V&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;letter-v&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#letter-v&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seneca earnestly approves of those constantly learning, determined for
self-improvement. To be a better man (or woman) is essential, however he warns
against doing it to seek attention, or for solely provoking others through
appearances or ways of living. This is profoundly accurate in an era, dominated
by FAANG mania, Instagram reelz and TikTok trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is fascinating how a philosopher born centuries ago accurately describes our
reality. Better yet shares his ideas on how to lead a simple life. Maybe, this
philosophy is deeply rooted in the essence of humanity, passed down through
generations; a promise of belonging to one race, one global community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seneca puts this beautifully: &lt;i&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our motto, as one knows, is to live in
conformity with nature.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some key points I found fascinating in this letter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admiring one&amp;rsquo;s way of life, and appreciate the beauty in its simplicity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admire one&amp;rsquo;s character and values, instead of their material possessions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seneca also highlights how &lt;em&gt;fear&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;hope&lt;/em&gt; march in unison &amp;ldquo;like a prisoner
and escort he is handcuffed to&amp;rdquo;. This theme is widely explored, so I would just
like to add how memory brings back the agony of fear, and as philosophical as
it sounds, one must live in the present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Letter VI&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;letter-vi&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#letter-vi&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this letter, Seneca writes to Lucilius that he observes not only
improvement, but also transformation within himself. While humbly admitting his
imperfections, Seneca admits the significance of sharing his feelings with his
friend (as discussed in a previous letter). Additionally, he highlights the
mutual benefit of exchanging insights through shared books. Knowledge is
valuable if shared, useless if held in secret. My philosophy on this remains.
Talking to someone each day and studying their character benefits more than
conversing with someone rarely. More often than not, to be your own friend too
is a wonderful idea of progress, atleast in theory. Nonetheless to share-it-all
with a friend is a priceless benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stoicism&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stoicism&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Phones, Too Much?</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/two-phones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 06:49:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/two-phones/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;When I was starting out as a working professional two years ago, I made a
pivotal decision that would redefine the way I interact with technologies. As a
privacy advocate and free software enthusiast, my aim was to reduce my reliance
on Google Services and other non-free software. This decision propelled me to
carry two phones to compartmentalize my online activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My primary phone is a Xiaomi Redmi Note 8, running LineageOS 18.1 and Android
11 (without Google Services). My work/non-free software running phone is a
Samsung M12 running Google Android 13 with OneUI version 5.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/redmi-samsung.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought Redmi a couple of months before covid-19. I loved how it boasted an
impressive camera, long-lasting battery, in-fact it checked every box in
the features department. The catch-22 was the intrusive personalized
advertising and the burden of pre-installed bloatware on the device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For obvious reasons, I switched to LineageOS because it offered a clean user
experience, particularly enjoying its UI. Additionally, it provided regular
security patches, a feature often lacking in the original MIUI. To this day, I
still receive security patches in lineageOS which is just awesome. The
trade-off sadly was a borked camera. * which I kind of got accustomed too :(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I relied on my Samsung Google Android device, particularly
for financial transactions via UPI, using proprietary spyware like WhatsApp to
be a part of pointless groups, order food through Zomato/Swiggy, book Uber, or
engage in work activities such as checking mail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amidst all of this, I was consciously using free and open source applications
(whenever possible) across both my devices. Some of them include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;F-Droid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brave Browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KDE Connect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mozilla Firefox (or any fork of it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Signal Messenger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A few Simple Mobile Tools applications - Contacts, Gallery, Dialer. ( do not
use it anymore since the apps are not open-source)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VLC Media Player&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Telegram FOSS (fork)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having two phones offer some other advantages which I can appreciate. Firstly,
I won&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about battery life. With two devices, I can distribute my
usage, lessening the strain on each battery. This ensures I always have a backup
available in case one device runs out of power. Also since I&amp;rsquo;m not particularly
fond of power banks, this setup suited me perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also prefer keeping my data locally rather than storing it in the cloud. So I
transitioned to storing all my media, documents, and important files on a hard
drive, with backups stored on my devices. This approach ensures my data is
easily accessible, under control and compartmentalized. This was perfect for
my threat modeling, however it does come at a cost of inconvenience. Carrying
two phones isn&amp;rsquo;t particularly comfortable, but it&amp;rsquo;s a compromise I&amp;rsquo;m willing to
make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yeah, I am glad to have made this decision, and I am grateful for the community
of developers and contributors who have built foss projects and made them
publicly available for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Free software is a matter of liberty, not price. To understand the concept, you should think of &amp;lsquo;free&amp;rsquo; as in &amp;lsquo;free speech,&amp;rsquo; not as in &amp;lsquo;free beer&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coffee Can Investing - A Review</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/coffee-can-investing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 11:58:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/coffee-can-investing/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;The best time to plant a tree was twenty years ago; the second best time is now.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I strongly beleive in the eight wonder of the world. It may be common sensical
for someone with good discipline, patience, and consistency that the secret
lies in waiting for the magic to unfold. The only way, my friend is paying the
price: &lt;em&gt;Time&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This magical reminder comes in a form of a book: Coffee Can Investing by Saurab
Mukherjea and his team, that have created a roadmap that captures the common
pitfalls of a common retail investor. A guide to make wise financial decisions
without compromising on your wants and desires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would highly recommend this book to someone who wants to filter out the noise
and focus on the goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Note:&lt;/u&gt; It may not be necessary for everyone to read the entire book, yet
skimming through to understand the core philosophy should do the trick.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bangalore Weather is Changing</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/bangalore-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 05:21:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/bangalore-weather/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;center&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/bangalore.jpg&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bengaluru is like a dear friend who gets along really well with anyone. She&amp;rsquo;s
known for her pleasant nature, creative mind, love for greens and hanging out
with people of diverse backgrounds. As someone who has lived with Bengaluru,
like many of us, who deeply value the essence of her character, I would reject
the idea if someone told me our beloved city could a face water crisis or reach
a scorching high temperature of 37 degrees this summer. (again)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all, we love her as we have seen her &amp;ndash; Grow as a quaint garden city to a
beautiful bustling metropolis. A city crowded by cars and cafes, ignoring the
effects of climate change and urbanization. And now our dear friend is weary. While
her heart beats with a passion for technology and innovation, she longs for a
break from endless development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ensure her sustainability for years to come, let us recognize her need to
prioritize self-care. Here are a few simple things you can do to nurture your
friendsip with Bengaluru.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conserve water by fixing leaks, taking shorter showers, turning off taps when not in use, and using water wisely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn off lights, fans, and electronic devices when not in use to conserve energy and lower utility bills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advocate for increased tree planting initiatives, and protest against cutting down trees for corporate profit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice proper waste management by segregating waste at the source into recyclables and non-recyclables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Opt for public transport whenever possible to alleviate carbon emissions and traffic congestion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spread awareness about environmental issues and the importance of sustainability through social media and other mediums.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Empire of Hell</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/empire-of-hell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 07:32:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/empire-of-hell/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;All the world&amp;rsquo;s a digital stage, &lt;br&gt;
and all the men and women merely scrollin&amp;rsquo; &amp;ndash; &lt;br&gt;
with no exits, their entrance is a screen &amp;ndash; &lt;br&gt;
a portal to their unseen dreams. broken&lt;br&gt;
and broke. impulse and hope-less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a double-edged sword. swallow whole&lt;br&gt;
pleasure and pain. one man at their time&lt;br&gt;
plays many parts of ruin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His acts being seven gigs of your intimate data.&lt;br&gt;
first phase of his playbook &amp;ndash; lure you in.&lt;br&gt;
Then gather and sell, finally build networth&lt;br&gt;
and tell the world, &amp;ldquo;I created an empire of hell.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>70 Hours per Week</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/70-hours-per-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 06:02:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/70-hours-per-week/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Infosys&lt;/em&gt; founder Narayana Murthy recently said that, young Indians must work 70 hours a week. &amp;ndash; a phenomenal recommendation from a prominent capitalist. I respect his achievements but a statement like this makes me want to question his intelligence or, take any of these wise old men seriously. His idea is if you want India to realize its economic potential every young Indian must say: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;This is my country. I want to work 70 hours a week.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt; 
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/modern-slave.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
 
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, you do not need to work 70 hours to realize its economic potential.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Maybe he forgot the part where the quality of life also plays a crucial part in economic development? Maybe higher wages would help? I don&amp;rsquo;t know, I am no expert. Nonetheless for the sake of argument, let&amp;rsquo;s explore the numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming a five-day work week, and subtracting 70 hours for work leaves out 50 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we allocate a bare minimum portion for essential activities like sleeping (averaging 8 hours a day) and meals (1.5 hours a day for three meals), we are left with barely a dozen hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have not included commuting, grooming or leisure time for that matter. it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to acknowledge that quality of life plays a significant role in economic development, which Murthy happily chose to ignore in his statement. Merely advocating for longer work hours without addressing other factors undermines overall well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and the nationalist angle is ridiculous. for the sake of India, you cannot work 14 hours a day? Oh come on?! Where&amp;rsquo;s all the energy draining? Don&amp;rsquo;t you tell me you are working two jobs?? Oh right, that&amp;rsquo;s called moonlighting. &lt;em&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t do that&lt;/em&gt;, that&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/tech/information-tech/infosys-warns-employees-on-moonlighting-says-could-lead-to-termination/articleshow/94169072.cms&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;unethical&lt;/a&gt;! You can only slog for us, because we are a big company and
you are our &lt;em&gt;modern slave&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.businessinsider.in/policy/economy/news/billionaire-businessman-says-young-indians-should-work-70-hours-a-week/articleshow/104787562.cms&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.businessinsider.in/policy/economy/news/billionaire-businessman-says-young-indians-should-work-70-hours-a-week/articleshow/104787562.cms&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.investopedia.com/ask/answers/032415/what-are-some-ways-economic-growth-can-be-achieved.asp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.investopedia.com/ask/answers/032415/what-are-some-ways-economic-growth-can-be-achieved.asp&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
