<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unchained Dev – Literature</title>
    <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/tags/literature/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Literature on Unchained Dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 15:44:33 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://unchaineddev.github.io/tags/literature/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Collecting</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/book-collecting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 15:44:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/book-collecting/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;I’ve collected several books over the years — ones I’ve read and cherished,
and others I’ve gathered for this atrocious bibliophilic hobby. But lately,
my eyes have open wide and long to witness the frame of a cluttered life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picture this: a minimalist having a collection of books that offer no fun.
Something that reaps no value, no joy, no excitement. Rather, it is silently
accumulating space, or worse, gathering dust on the shelf. Books are meant
to be read. And if it is read, it has fulfilled its purpose. If they’re worth
revisiting, so be it — but how often does that really happen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a world where there are a multitude of options, I have reached a point of reason.
A steady realisation that collecting for the sake of ownership is no longer enough.
It feels like a race &amp;ndash; maybe against others or maybe against oneself. Maybe it is me,
maybe it is the greedy heart driven by a deep and unrelenting passion of art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pick up old novels I read years ago — those supposedly philosophical, self-improving,
and healing works, disguised as pure entertainment. Mental note to self: &lt;em&gt;No more of these.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember a particular lazy sunday from a dozens of sundays, where I perch on the floor
and sort the paperbacks. The excitement of cataloguing, or lack thereof. This desire to turn
pages and finish the unfinished business is immeasurable. It is like buying lost time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a through inspection of my shelf, I faced an undeniable truth. a man&amp;rsquo;s books is his mindset.
Seneca said it best: The importance of picking the right books and authors matters, because the
quality of the books you read directly impacts your character and wisdom. In the same breath,
here&amp;rsquo;s a paradox: I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have come across the brilliant stoicness of Seneca, if I had not explored
the seas of option. The idea is to explore, nourish, and appreciate art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After collecting over hundred books over the past few years, I have decided to part ways with most
of the books, or rather exchange them for (better?) alternatives. I’ll focus on works by authors
who have shaped my mind — writers like Dostoevsky, Kafka, Wilde, Poe, Austen, Shakespeare, and even
contemporary voices like King, Murakami, or even Roy. These are the voices that resonate, that stay with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, I will read widely, but for the sake of collecting them, I will not. I will read
something novel, something fresh, something that refreshes and transforms the mind.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ray of Bengal</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/ray-of-bengal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 12:42:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/ray-of-bengal/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;When my brother visited &lt;em&gt;Kolkata&lt;/em&gt;, he asked me what he could bring back for me
from the city. Unaware of the local specialties, I asked him to get me some
books. You see, I have always been intrigued by Satyajit Ray&amp;rsquo;s cinema, with
masterpieces like &lt;em&gt;The Apu Trilogy&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Devi&lt;/em&gt; standing out as notable
classics. However, I had not explored his written works until recently. So, I
asked him to bring me a souvenir in the form of &lt;em&gt;The Curse of the Goddess&lt;/em&gt;.
(Feluda #16), amongst other couple books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I finally had the chance to read it, and I must say it was a remarkable
mystery. Ray demonstrates his exceptional storytelling skills, keeping the
reader engaged while maintaining suspense until the very end. I would not be
exaggerating if I said this detective story is like anything you’d find in any
of Agatha Christie’s works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re a fan of detective novels by Christie, Doyle, or similar authors, I
highly recommend diving into one of the Feluda stories, w/o which.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ICURMT.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letters From A Stoic</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/letters-from-a-stoic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 07:54:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/letters-from-a-stoic/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;This post contains letters from &lt;em&gt;Seneca&lt;/em&gt;, a Stoic philosopher of Ancient Rome,
and my thoughts on his philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Stoicism?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     Stoics identified the path to achieving it
[ good spirit ] with a life spent practicing the four virtues in everyday life:
&lt;br&gt;
     wisdom, courage, temperance or moderation, and
justice, and living in accordance with nature. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Letter II&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;letter-ii&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#letter-ii&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/book.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400px&#34;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seneca&amp;rsquo;s second letter is addressed to Lucilius, emphasising significance of
settling one&amp;rsquo;s self and deriving joy from solitude. He advises against
consuming books from different authors, instead &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;focusing on authors whose
genius is unquestionable&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would slightly disagree with him on this point. There is no doubt genius
writers would have a great effect on one&amp;rsquo;s mind, however you cannot ignore the
impact of the human experience. If you are reading something not-so-genius but
you learn a valuable lesson from it, I would argue it would be a wise choice.
While Seneca&amp;rsquo;s analogy of a wound not healing if subjected to experiments of
several ointments, or a plant weakening from constant uprooting is compelling,
engaging with a multitude of viewpoints and getting perspective deepens your
understanding of things. With this in mind, I would not say reading a lot of
garbage self-help authors or a bunch of phony writers would do your life any
good. Picking the right authors is without a doubt a good first step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seneca also suggests focusing more on the quality than the quantity of books.
This resonates with my philosphy and it is something I really struggle with
sometimes. Whenever I start a book, my heart &lt;strong&gt;wants&lt;/strong&gt; to finish it (as most of
us would like to). However, this is a key point to keep in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;i&gt;To read that brings pleasure, and to let go of books that cause pain.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To use this knowledge as a shield against life&amp;rsquo;s adversities and cultivate the
habit of resilience is valuable advice. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t agree more with Seneca when
he says, &amp;ldquo;It is not the man who has too little who is poor, but the one who
hankers after more&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Letter III&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;letter-iii&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#letter-iii&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember the popular proverb, &lt;em&gt;A friend in need is a friend indeed&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this letter, Seneca addresses Lucilius&amp;rsquo;s distrust towards his friend, and
&lt;em&gt;dramatically&lt;/em&gt; questions him if he &amp;ldquo;actually&amp;rdquo; called him a friend or if it was
merely out of courtesy. This debate evokes a point in my life, when I stood by
this philosophy of &lt;em&gt;true friendship&lt;/em&gt;. (as ridiculous as it sounds) I reserved
the title of a &lt;em&gt;friend&lt;/em&gt; with those I shared a deep friendship, while others,
less intimately known, remained acquaintances. The significance of words may be
overlooked in today&amp;rsquo;s world, yet the value words hold must remain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/friends.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400px&#34;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, &lt;em&gt;Friendship&lt;/em&gt; is a bond built on trust, where we willingly place our
hearts and souls at our friend&amp;rsquo;s feet, trusting they will not deceive us.
Overcoming fear of betrayal demands reflecting the same trust we have in
ourselves. Seneca offers timeless wisdom on this matter, advising against both
indiscriminately confiding in everyone and keeping secrets from our closest
friends. Certainly judgement must precede freely sharing thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seneca believes being busy in life doesn&amp;rsquo;t always equate to productivity,
rather signifies a troubled mind. Likewise, condemning all activity leads to
laziness and not a relaxed mind. He advocates for striking a balance and
suggests looking towards nature for relaxation. Below is a quote I really found
interesting in this letter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Some men have shrunk so far into dark corners that objects in broad daylight
seem quite blurred to them&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Letter V&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;letter-v&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#letter-v&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seneca earnestly approves of those constantly learning, determined for
self-improvement. To be a better man (or woman) is essential, however he warns
against doing it to seek attention, or for solely provoking others through
appearances or ways of living. This is profoundly accurate in an era, dominated
by FAANG mania, Instagram reelz and TikTok trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is fascinating how a philosopher born centuries ago accurately describes our
reality. Better yet shares his ideas on how to lead a simple life. Maybe, this
philosophy is deeply rooted in the essence of humanity, passed down through
generations; a promise of belonging to one race, one global community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seneca puts this beautifully: &lt;i&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our motto, as one knows, is to live in
conformity with nature.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some key points I found fascinating in this letter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admiring one&amp;rsquo;s way of life, and appreciate the beauty in its simplicity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admire one&amp;rsquo;s character and values, instead of their material possessions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seneca also highlights how &lt;em&gt;fear&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;hope&lt;/em&gt; march in unison &amp;ldquo;like a prisoner
and escort he is handcuffed to&amp;rdquo;. This theme is widely explored, so I would just
like to add how memory brings back the agony of fear, and as philosophical as
it sounds, one must live in the present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Letter VI&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;letter-vi&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#letter-vi&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this letter, Seneca writes to Lucilius that he observes not only
improvement, but also transformation within himself. While humbly admitting his
imperfections, Seneca admits the significance of sharing his feelings with his
friend (as discussed in a previous letter). Additionally, he highlights the
mutual benefit of exchanging insights through shared books. Knowledge is
valuable if shared, useless if held in secret. My philosophy on this remains.
Talking to someone each day and studying their character benefits more than
conversing with someone rarely. More often than not, to be your own friend too
is a wonderful idea of progress, atleast in theory. Nonetheless to share-it-all
with a friend is a priceless benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Letter VII&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;letter-vii&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#letter-vii&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a world driven through trends, events and content, there is always a chaotic
mind. Though Seneca highlights in this letter that consorting with a mass crowd
is harmful, I beleive mingling with the wrong crowd is far more perilous. It&amp;rsquo;s
often said that one&amp;rsquo;s character is significantly influenced by the five closest
people one associates with. Therefore, it is essential to be picky in that respect.
Someone who improves your character; Someone who you can improve. A process of
mutual improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;center&gt;A few is enough for me; so is one; and so is none. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stoicism&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stoicism&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ram&#39;s Wise Mind</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/rams-wise-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 19:27:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/rams-wise-mind/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Sarat Chandra Chattopadhyay&amp;rsquo;s short story &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Ram&amp;rsquo;s Wise Mind&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; (or Ramer Shumoti) is a poignant story of a seventeen year old boy, &lt;em&gt;Ramlaal&lt;/em&gt; and his sister-in-law &lt;em&gt;Narayani&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;photoswipe&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/rams-wise-mind.jpg&#34; width=&#34;250px&#34;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though Ram is troublesome and mischievous in the eyes of many, he is not to Narayani. She assumes the role of a mother-figure to him, adding a layer of complexity and tenderness to their relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chattopadhyay&amp;rsquo;s storytelling shines as he paints a vivid picture of the emotional landscape between Ram and Narayani. Their bond becomes a testament to the enduring power of human connection, defying societal norms and expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those seeking a literary experience that elegantly captures the intricacies of human emotion, this short story is a compelling choice.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Story Of My Experiments With Truth</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/gandhi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:19:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/gandhi/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;In hindsight it might seem like we are not affected by history, however, for the most part we are. Take a currency note for instance. Did you ever reflect on the man behind the note?
His truths, legacy, philosophy, or principles for that matter, that left an indelible mark on our history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/rupee-note.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400px&#34;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
 
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to share my review on Gandhi&amp;rsquo;s biography, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Story Of My Experiments With Truth&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/em&gt;
There are 5 parts in his book, and I will go over all the key learnings from the Mahatma himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Part 1 - Early Life&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;part-1---early-life&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#part-1---early-life&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gandhi was born in Porbandar to a devout Hindu family. His father, Karam Chand was an esteemed minister and his mother, Putlibai, a religious and an intelligent woman. It was from his mother Gandhi reveals, that shaped his spiritual beliefs in the years to come. He was married at the age of thirteen, a child marriage commonplace during the time that weighed heavily on his conscience. a bitter truth he remorsely conveys that cast a shadow on his understanding of personal freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the chapters of &lt;strong&gt;Part 1&lt;/strong&gt;, Gandhi confesses his shy nature and the ingenious ways he overcame it. He was an introvert finding delight in books. While I was eagerly flipping through the pages, it was abundantly clear to me that Gandhi was exceptionally well-read. He devoured knowledge across diverse subjects. Religion, Vegetarianism, Philosophy, you name it. In the truest sense, he was honest unlike any other. It takes an honest man some grit to reveal to his readers his shortcomings. Our man does that throughout these pages. Starting with an incident in his school days, where he was (wait for it) accused of lying! He had skipped a gymnastics class to be a nurse to his sick father. He states that it was the last careless incident of his school days, however, not of his childhood days though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/young-gandhi.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400px&#34;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
 
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are moments in young Gandhi&amp;rsquo;s life filled with his share of regrets: first, of an incident where he secretly stole coppers from his servant&amp;rsquo;s pocket money to smoke cigarettes. Another of any ill-formed friendship; a friend whom his mother, elder brother and wife warned to stay away from. He reveals that the reason for being friends with his elder brother&amp;rsquo;s classmate was to &amp;ldquo;reform him&amp;rdquo;. Alas, his intent did not go as planned. Instead he was influenced by him to be a meat-eater. He conveys his regret on taking this path briefly, although I felt maybe it would make him physically stronger while fighting against the British later (hehe just kidding!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After his father&amp;rsquo;s demise, and completing of his matriculation, he was presented with an opportunity to study in England. It struck me that it was only a century ago when Gandhi set his sight on England, and his caste people were agitated for him moving abroad, entitling him as an &lt;em&gt;outcast&lt;/em&gt;. This serves as a reminder of the fluid nature of societal perception. it is just a matter of time, like they say, for the perspective to evolve. So off goes the outcast, leaving his wife and his first born: To England.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In England at last, Gandhi shares his brief encounters with the cultural differences, immersing himself in studying law, learning how to be &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;an English Gentleman&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;, and exploring vegetarianism. a narrative that unfolded delightfully. One key thing in this part of the book that caught my intrigue was Gandhi&amp;rsquo;s habit of accounting. He tracked his expenses precisely and succeeded in exercising it with large amounts as well. This is one thing I feel we lack in the consumeristic culture we live in today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, for my readers who work a corporate job, here is something that may or may not apply to you. The following lesson was given to Gandhi by a Mr. Mehta, verbatim the first lesson on European etiquette &amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;Do not talk loudly, never address people &amp;ldquo;sir&amp;rdquo; whilst speaking to them, as we do in India; only servants and subordinates address theirs masters that way.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/sir.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400px&#34;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
 
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the context of working in a corporate job, it&amp;rsquo;s just bad practise to do that. if you are a fresh graduate, it should take you a while, but what I find madly preposterous is people with a work experience exceeding a culinary hen still address their senior management people as &amp;lsquo;sir&amp;quot; even though they have asked them &lt;strong&gt;NOT&lt;/strong&gt; to! (I can recall three instances as I write this when a senior manager asked people not to call him sir!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a mystery to me on what they achieve from the disrespect they give their senior management. If a person demands to be called sir, that&amp;rsquo;s another story. You can ruffle their feathers nonetheless. Why? Because calling someone sir* is awkward, and outdated to say the least. However, I digress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* on circumstance of a corporate job. the usage on other places is debatable, yet I feel it polite only when you do not know a person&amp;rsquo;s name for instance. (totally avoidable though!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Part 2 - Experience in Africa&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;part-2---experience-in-africa&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#part-2---experience-in-africa&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the annals of history, Gandhi&amp;rsquo;s encounter with racism in South Africa remains a poignant chapter. In this section of the book, he shares his experience at length about being ejected out of his first-class passenger seat, his battle against color prejudice and racism, his Christian contacts whose support helped him deeply in his quest for finding God and spiritual enlightenment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To acquire true knowledge, Gandhi says, one must have a guru. a mentor to mold one&amp;rsquo;s progress and self-growth. A result of which yields a moral standing and strength. He pays tribute to Raychandbhai, who taught him the importance of self-discipline and truthfulness to Gopal Krishna Gokhale&amp;rsquo;s influence that shaped his political activism. Additionally, he speaks of other notable figures namely Leo Tolstoy, whose prose had influenced his view of the world profoundly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/mentor.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400px&#34;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
 
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of, I think finding the right Guru is a challenge. While one may lack the knowledge in a particular field, another would be too occupied to fulfill their own responsibilities. I think of it as a good thing though. In today&amp;rsquo;s digital age, there is a wealth of information you can acquire on the internet. The goal should be in this long walk, a constant strive for self-improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing to note is that Gandhi&amp;rsquo;s prose is deeply personal. If you delve into his work, it is close to impossible to not be affected by it. I must say, our hero was without a question an imperfect man. Despite all of this, his truths continue to resonate within us, a testament to his enduring power of prose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His influence is far-fetched akin to the arms of a bapu, literally. In Africa, He unites all the Indians under a sole cause: Fair Treatment. It was indeed the rise of Mahatma Gandhi, not just as a political leader, but the voice for the voiceless. A public service barrister. In his own words, and I quote, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;To find the better side of human nature, a lawyer must unite parties, river asunder.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Part 3 - His Philosophy&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;part-3---his-philosophy&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#part-3---his-philosophy&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gandhi&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;self-reliant&lt;/em&gt; nature is possibly what I admire most about the man. His ability to perform tasks like washing his own clothes or cutting his own hair. It came at the cost of ridicule, yet his determination was unhindered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While he stayed with Gokhale, he learns of the dedication required to do public service, and how his hectic schedule restrained him from taking long walks or exercise. He thus emphasizes the reader to prioritize one&amp;rsquo;s health and well-being. This one I liked too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there are some aspects of his philosophy that I find unnecessary.
For instance, he believes, vows don&amp;rsquo;t close the door to freedom but open them.
And caring for children is inconsistent (more on this later) with doing public work, which again is quite the contrary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When faced with adversity, Gandhi doesn&amp;rsquo;t succumb. He recounts a tough moment when his son, Manilal fell ill, and the doctor prescribed eggs and chicken broth, which is contrary to Gandhi&amp;rsquo;s vegetarianism principles. This situation truly tested his conviction. Nevertheless, Gandhi perseveres and sticks to his values, and &lt;em&gt;cares&lt;/em&gt; for his son, leaving no stone unturned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/veggies.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400px&#34;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I beleive in a balanced diet. In fact I encourage cooked green vegetables as an essential in your meal. I say this, for Gandhi advocates self-control in every aspect, including diet. According to him, control of the palate &amp;ndash; simple, spiceless, and uncooked foods &amp;ndash; to restrain the senses and passions of life. I disagree with this perspective for the most part. It reminds me of a quote from one of my favorite authors of the 19th century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The only way to get rid of a temptation is to yield to it. Resist it, and your soul grows sick with longing for the things it has forbidden to itself, with desire for what its monstrous laws have made monstrous and unlawful.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find some of these teachings for the modern life challenging, and I daresay unrealistic for everyone. Everyone. for a great man like Gandhi, it&amp;rsquo;s a breeze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another aspect of Gandhi&amp;rsquo;s principle I can appreciate and encourage though,
is his emphasis on cleanliness  and sanitation. Despite his efforts on hygiene on third-class passenger trains or places of the divine, the reality even today is far from ideal. He proposes solutions, yet the unsanitary habits we have accustomed ourselves with is disheartening. It is nothing, but a lost cause.
From my experience nothing much has changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part 4 &amp;amp; 5 &amp;ndash; soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt; 
&lt;ins&gt;&lt;i&gt;Quote of the month&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;i&gt;
I have nothing new to teach the world, 
Truth and non-violence are as old as the hills.
&lt;/i&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Personal Library</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/library/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/library/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;This page contains a list of books from my personal library. While I don&amp;rsquo;t consider myself to be a book hoarder, I do have a reasonable number to display them here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if you have any questions or want to recommend or review any book, you can do that &lt;a href=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/contact&#34; &gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the books are categorized by genre, and each genre is arranged chronologically based on the author&amp;rsquo;s name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fiction&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;fiction&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#fiction&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;figure style=&#34;float: right; margin-left: 80px; margin-right: 200px; margin-bottom: 10px; width:160px&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/library/crime-and-punishment.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adiga, Arvind &amp;ndash; The White Tiger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alcott, Louisa May &amp;ndash; Little Women&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Archer, Jeffrey &amp;ndash; A Prisoner of Birth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Austen, Jane &amp;ndash; Pride and Prejudice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bond, Ruskin &amp;ndash; The Blue Umbrella&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bond, Ruskin &amp;ndash; The Girl on the Train&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brontë, Charlotte &amp;ndash; Jane Eyre&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brontë, Emily &amp;ndash; Wuthering heights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chattopadhyay, Sarat Chandra &amp;ndash; Datta (Betrothed)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chattopadhyay, Sarat Chandra &amp;ndash; Ramer Shumoti (Ram&amp;rsquo;s Wise Mind)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christie, Agatha &amp;ndash; The Murder on the Links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christie, Agatha &amp;ndash; The Mysterious Affair at Styles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christie, Agatha &amp;ndash; Where the light lasts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coelho, Paulo &amp;ndash; Adultery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coelho, Paulo &amp;ndash; The Devil and Miss Prym&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coelho, Paulo &amp;ndash; The Spy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coelho, Paulo &amp;ndash; Veronica Decides to Die&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conrad, Joseph &amp;ndash; Heart of Darkness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dickens, Charles &amp;ndash; A Christmas Carol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dostoyevsky, Fyodor &amp;ndash; Crime and Punishment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doyle, Arthur Conan &amp;ndash; The Complete Novels of Sherlock Holmes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure style=&#34;float: right; margin-left: 80px; margin-right: 200px; margin-bottom: 10px; width:160px&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/library/the-metamorphosis.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doyle, Aruthur Conan &amp;ndash; The Hound of the Baskervilles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fitzgerald, Scott F. &amp;ndash; The Great Gatsby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flynn, Gillian &amp;ndash; Gone Girl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flynn, Gillian &amp;ndash; The Grownup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forster, E.M &amp;ndash; A Passage to India&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ghosh, Amitav &amp;ndash; The Shadow Lines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hemingway, Ernest &amp;ndash; The Old Man and the Sea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Henry, O &amp;ndash; Best of O&amp;rsquo;Henry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hosseini, Khaled &amp;ndash; A Thousand Splendid Suns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jerome, Jerome K. &amp;ndash; Three Men in a Boat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kafka, Franz &amp;ndash; Metamorphosis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kafka, Franz &amp;ndash; The Trial&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;King, Stephen &amp;ndash; The Shining&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;King, Stephen &amp;ndash; IT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kipling, Rudyard &amp;ndash; The Jungle Book&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lee, Harper &amp;ndash; To Kill a Mockingbird&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manto, Saadat Hasan &amp;ndash; Selected Short Stories (Aatish Taseer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure style=&#34;float: right; margin-left: 80px; margin-right: 200px; margin-bottom: 10px; width:160px&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/library/kafka-on-the-shore.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Morrison, Toni &amp;ndash; Beloved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Murakami, Haruki &amp;ndash; Birthday Girl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Murakami, Haruki &amp;ndash; Kafka on the Shore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Murthy, Sudha &amp;ndash; Three Thousand Stitches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nabokov, Vladimir &amp;ndash; Lance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Orwell, George &amp;ndash; 1984&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Orwell, George - Animal Farm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poe, Edgar Allan &amp;ndash; Selected Tales&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plath, Sylvia &amp;ndash; The Bell Jar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Puzo, Mario &amp;ndash; The Godfather&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ray, Satyajit &amp;ndash; Sonar Kella (The Golden Fortress)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ray, Satyajit &amp;ndash; Chhinnamastar Abhishap (The Curse of the Goddess)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roy, Arundhathi &amp;ndash; The God of Small Things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salinger, J.D &amp;ndash; Catcher in the Rye&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shelly, Mary &amp;ndash; Frankenstein&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Singh, Khushwant &amp;ndash; Train to Pakistan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smith, Zadie - White Teeth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stoker, Bram &amp;ndash; Dracula&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tagore, Rabindranath - Nashtanirh (Broken Nest)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twain, Mark &amp;ndash; The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twain, Mark &amp;ndash; The Adventures of Tom Sawyer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wells, H.G &amp;ndash; The Time Machine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wharton, Edith &amp;ndash; The Age of Innocence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wilde, Oscar &amp;ndash; The Picture of Dorian Grey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Non-Fiction&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;non-fiction&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#non-fiction&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;figure style=&#34;float: right; margin-left: 80px; margin-right: 200px; margin-bottom: 10px; width:160px&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/library/night-walks.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Achebe, Chinua &amp;ndash; Africa&amp;rsquo;s Tarnished Name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Albom, Mitch &amp;ndash; Tuesdays with Morrie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allen, James &amp;ndash; As a Man Thinketh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ambedkar, B.R &amp;ndash; Ambedkar&amp;rsquo;s India&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brandt, Charles &amp;ndash; I Heard You Paint Houses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Benyamin &amp;ndash; Goat Days&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dickens, Charles &amp;ndash; Night Walks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Durrani, Tehmina &amp;ndash; My Feudal Lord&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frank, Anne &amp;ndash; The Diary of a Young Girl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gandhi, Mahatma &amp;ndash; The Story of my Experiments with Truth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grover, Ashneer &amp;ndash; Doglapan: The Hard Truth about Life and Start-ups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marx, Karl &amp;ndash; The Communist Manifesto&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mukherjea, Saurabh / Ranjan, Rakshit / Uniyal, Pranab - Coffee Can Investing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prabhakar, Parakala - The Crooked Timber Of New India&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Singh, Khushwant &amp;ndash; The End of India&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tagore, Rabindranath &amp;ndash; Nationalism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tzu, Sun &amp;ndash; The Art of War&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Philosophy&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;philosophy&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#philosophy&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aristotle - Poetics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Camus, Albert &amp;ndash; The Myth of Sisyphus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nietzsche, Friedrich Wilhelm &amp;ndash; Thus Spake Zarathustra&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seneca - Letters from a Stoic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Plays&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;plays&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#plays&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;figure style=&#34;float: right; margin-left: 80px; margin-right: 200px; margin-bottom: 10px; width:150px&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/library/william-shakespeare.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christie, Agatha &amp;ndash; The Mousetrap &amp;amp; Selected Plays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Miller, Arthur &amp;ndash; Death of a Salesman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shakespeare, William &amp;ndash; Julius Caesar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shakespeare, William &amp;ndash; Macbeth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shakespeare, William &amp;ndash; Othello&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shakespeare, William &amp;ndash; The Comedy of Errors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wilde, Oscar &amp;ndash; The Importance of Being Earnest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Poetry&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;poetry&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#poetry&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brontë, Emily &amp;ndash; The Night is Darkening Round Me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hafez &amp;ndash; The Nightingales are drunk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gibran, Kahlil &amp;ndash; The Prophet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keats, John &amp;ndash; The Eve of St.Agnes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shakespeare, William &amp;ndash; Sonnets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whitman, Walt &amp;ndash; On the Beach at Night Alone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
