<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unchained Dev – technology</title>
    <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in technology on Unchained Dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 19:20:51 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://unchaineddev.github.io/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Vision Pro is Trash</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/apple-vision-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 19:20:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/apple-vision-pro/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/apple-vision-pro.jpeg&#34; width=&#34;300px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever had of something called a Bad Apple? Well you might be amazed to hear that all the normies have assembled together again to admire a new addition to their walled-garden, The all new VR Headset, or as apple
likes to call it their first &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apple.com/in/newsroom/2023/06/introducing-apple-vision-pro/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;spatial computer&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This device is supposed to be put on your head so that you seamlessly switch between the physical and digital world. The best part about it is you can take it out after two minutes, because it is such a headache to have it on. If you don&amp;rsquo;t believe me, try putting a 500 gram object on your head - which will be lighter than this headset. it is just too unnecessary. they really expect people to keep wearing this like a bunch of zombies; And whenever they feel like activating their digital world, it is a button away, all of which is controlled by (you guessed it) &lt;em&gt;apple!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/normie-using-apple-vision-pro.png&#34; width=&#34;500px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apple.com/apple-vision-pro/guided-tour/&#34;&gt;Watch Full Video&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you cannot control though are apple&amp;rsquo;s innovative decisions. Rightfully so, they want their customers to have the best experience, and you trust them, right? Well then, you just need to pinch yourself, because what you are having is a dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;this new piece of tech is ridiculously priced, and isn&amp;rsquo;t worth the price. As the apple joke goes, one has to sell a kidney to buy their one product. But with &lt;em&gt;Apple Vision Pro&lt;/em&gt;, you would most likely have to sell both.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
