<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unchained Dev – Politics</title>
    <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/tags/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on Unchained Dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 20:40:58 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://unchaineddev.github.io/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Crooked Timber Of New India</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/new-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 20:40:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/new-india/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;I stumbled upon a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DLy3YOJeogA&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;YouTube video&lt;/a&gt;
featuring &lt;em&gt;Mr. Parakala Prabhakar&lt;/em&gt;, interviewed by few of the last esteemed
journalists left in our country today: &lt;em&gt;Mr. Karan Thapar&lt;/em&gt;. The discussion delved
into the current state of politics, economy and social fabric of our country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. &lt;em&gt;Parakala Prabhakar&lt;/em&gt; is a political activist, &lt;em&gt;economist&lt;/em&gt;, scholar, and
author. Parakala, if you are unaware, is also the husband of the current
Finance Minister, &lt;em&gt;Nirmala Sitharaman&lt;/em&gt;. This adds an intriguing level to this
discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parakala&amp;rsquo;s unapologetic honesty and unwavering stance against the Modi Regime
is profoundly shocking, yet not entirely unprecedented. It was really
compelling to see a man speak truths in a world of men and women intolerant of
criticism in any shape or form. My decision to to pick his book, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Crooked
Timber Of New India&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; was with a desire for a deeper understanding of our
polity, economy and progress as a nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his book, he speaks in length of the failures of the Modi Government,
particularly the false promises to reduce unemployment, abolish corruption,
demonetization of currency notes that broke the backbone of our economy,
mishandling of COVID-19, amongst others. In a chapter, Parakala skillfully
employs the &amp;ldquo;Rabbit-duck illusion&amp;rdquo; as an analogy to depict the state of affairs
within the ruling party. I found it very clever and insightful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mishandling of COVID-19 by the Central Government is unforgettable. It is marked
in history, as they conveniently prioritized their crony capitalists over
public good. The illusionary schemes were merely for show, nothing helped
citizens. Poverty was at an all-time high since 1990s. 75 Million were pushed
to poverty, and the government did nothing but praise itself for &amp;ldquo;2.5 Cr Jabs&amp;rdquo;.
Parakala shares one story of a young boy victim to the poverty of the New
India, and then shares a powerful quote by Gandhiji which made me feel hopeful
of a future leader that would bring about change like this &amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Whenever you are faced with a difficult situation, imagine the poorest of the
poor and see if your decision brings a smile to their faces.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another fascinating chapter was: &amp;ldquo;Egocracy: Digital Freedom and Data Privacy&amp;rdquo;.
Parakala deeply examines the rising internet shutdowns, concerning accumulation
of data from Big Tech Companies collected for government use, pervasive erosion
of privacy, content moderation, removing posts by targeting critics, and data
breaches. I was happy to read a well-researched and accurate account of the
state of privacy in India. It felt like a breath of fresh air to read this
essay, and I was glad to realize people like Parakala exist, to fight against
lost causes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of lost causes, there is a lot of horrible attempts to rewrite and
portray history. The fear of an incompetant leader swaying masses through media
and his oracy, calling his reign as &lt;em&gt;The New India&lt;/em&gt;, and what ever came before
him were all but an underwhelming effect says a lot about him. In addition, the
push for a singular national identity at the expense of democratic values is a
cause for deep concern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is lot of wistful politics at play, rather than focusing on pressing
issues. Obvious one is polarizing Hindu-Muslim dynamics, push for a singular
Hindu-Hindi identity for being hailed as truly Indian, population control of a
certain community by stoking fear about an imagined scenario of numerical
equality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading this book, you feel a void in your heart. Something you cannot
fill, something you cannot mend. The state of affairs in India today as
portrayed by Parakala makes your blood boil. Sadly, this is a harsh reality we
as citizens have conformed to. Yet, amidst the despair, the solution is a call
to action. Between we &lt;em&gt;as a people&lt;/em&gt; against governments who divide us by caste,
creed or religion. Against media houses who spread propaganda and cannot stand
criticism of the government. It is also a battle against the people amongst us
who undermine democracy and stay hidden behind an idelogy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop Using Whatsapp</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/stop-using-whatsapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 21:05:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/stop-using-whatsapp/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s disheartening to go against what is a lost cause. To tell someone to stop using whatsapp
in India is like ripping off their right to communicate freely. Nobody cares about privacy around here.
If someone likes me tells them their favorite messaging app is invasive, they tend to prompt questions that
imply I may have something to hide. Well in truth, Whatsapp is a closed-source, zuckbook-backed, data-mining company,
which in many ways is compromised. With this in mind, you cannot argue that you don&amp;rsquo;t care about privacy
and it is stupid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edward Snowden said it best: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Arguing that you don&amp;rsquo;t care about privacy becaue you have nothing to hide is no different
than saying you don&amp;rsquo;t care about free speech because you have nothing to say&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is worse?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://whatsapp.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Whatsapp&lt;/a&gt; falsely claims to be a private messaging app, providing &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;end-to-end encryption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
to your messages. In reality, Whatsapp moderators&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; can read your messages, and they love to share your metadata
with law enforcement and other third-party companies, not only because it has to comply, or earn a profit, but to build
a relationship map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A relationship map is an identity that can be derived from just who you associate with, which basically just
cancels out the encryption and privacy claim. One could argue that the constant lies is the problem, but you
need to ask yourself, if whatsapp was a person, would you trust it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a fun fact: The Zuck himself does not use whatsapp. Yet we Indians are accustomed to
&lt;em&gt;Good Morning&lt;/em&gt; texts and &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;forwards&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; that our minds have become numb, like the lizard person dumb
founded by gathering all that data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree it is hard to break loose from this dopamine induced eco-system. After all, the primary reason why
people can&amp;rsquo;t stop using whatsapp is because everyone is on it, akin to the same problem instagram suffers with.
If your friends and family use whatsapp, instagram and zuckbook, one must be mad to think of using an alternative.
Moreover, to succeed at bringing all your friends and family into a different platform is like compelling them to
the dance floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of those gotcha moments of the Zuck; a trap designed to chain your freedom. But if you are someone
who values privacy and respects yourself, I would suggest you to try Signal and encourage others to use it.
It is a better app for personal and intimate conversations with your friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gizmodo.com/whatsapp-moderators-can-read-your-messages-1847629241&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://gizmodo.com/whatsapp-moderators-can-read-your-messages-1847629241&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Support for Palestine</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/support-for-palestine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 20:09:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/support-for-palestine/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;All the big news organizations are known for manipulating facts and having biased opinions. If you think there are not taking a side, you are overly optimistic. Moreover, relying on a for-profit major news organizations is akin to burying one&amp;rsquo;s head in the sand and trusting whatever information comes along.
It is a no-brainer. Their support for Israel makes it even more clear of their ignorance. More civilians are killed by Israel and they will never show you that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An eye for an eye makes the whole world blind&lt;/em&gt;. They will never tell you &lt;em&gt;Hamas&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;strong&gt;NOT&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Palestine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to news organizations, there are a certain &amp;ldquo;smart&amp;rdquo; people which I have found myself losing a lot of respect for. Despite their extensive knowledge in their respective fields, it&amp;rsquo;s disheartening to see they do not see the bigger picture and prioritize personal interests over basic human rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their unwavering support for Israel is crystal clear that they cannot be trusted. It is disturbing to see their indifference towards the consequences of Israeli actions on Palestinian civilians, especially considering that over half of the population comprises children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally I oppose the use of social media, however in a time like this, people who actively use it must not remain silent on such matters, considering how swiftly people post about trending topics. It&amp;rsquo;s crucial to recognize that silence can inadvertently contribute to the perpetuation of hatred.
If it does not happen to you, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you need to turn a blink eye, and that is the message of this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt; 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social tensions after World War II convinced the &amp;ldquo;Zionist Jews&amp;rdquo; that they need their own country.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. 20 years later, here&amp;rsquo;s how Palestine occupied area looks like:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/palestine.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400px&#34;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Albert Einstein on Palestine: &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I am in favor of Palestine being developed as a Jewish Homeland but not as a separate state.
It seems to me a matter of simple common sense that we cannot ask to be given political rule over Palestine where two thirds of the population are not Jewish.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; January 19, 1946&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many Jews (except the Zionists)&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; are still of the opinion to &lt;em&gt;free Palestine&lt;/em&gt; and to live in &lt;em&gt;peace&lt;/em&gt; with each other.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vox.com/2018/11/20/18080016/israel-zionism-war-1948&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.vox.com/2018/11/20/18080016/israel-zionism-war-1948&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://countercurrents.org/2023/10/einstein-cited-equally-horrific-terrorist-massacre-of-arabs-usa-origin-of-killing-in-palestine/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://countercurrents.org/2023/10/einstein-cited-equally-horrific-terrorist-massacre-of-arabs-usa-origin-of-killing-in-palestine/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/oct/19/jewish-protest-israel-gaza-washington-dc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/oct/19/jewish-protest-israel-gaza-washington-dc&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.annefrank.org/en/topics/antisemitism/are-all-jews-zionists/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.annefrank.org/en/topics/antisemitism/are-all-jews-zionists/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
