<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unchained Dev – Poetry</title>
    <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/tags/poetry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Poetry on Unchained Dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 07:54:08 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://unchaineddev.github.io/tags/poetry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Letters From A Stoic</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/letters-from-a-stoic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 07:54:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/letters-from-a-stoic/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;This post contains letters from &lt;em&gt;Seneca&lt;/em&gt;, a Stoic philosopher of Ancient Rome,
and my thoughts on his philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Stoicism?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     Stoics identified the path to achieving it
[ good spirit ] with a life spent practicing the four virtues in everyday life:
&lt;br&gt;
     wisdom, courage, temperance or moderation, and
justice, and living in accordance with nature. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Letter II&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;letter-ii&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#letter-ii&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/book.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400px&#34;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seneca&amp;rsquo;s second letter is addressed to Lucilius, emphasising significance of
settling one&amp;rsquo;s self and deriving joy from solitude. He advises against
consuming books from different authors, instead &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;focusing on authors whose
genius is unquestionable&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would slightly disagree with him on this point. There is no doubt genius
writers would have a great effect on one&amp;rsquo;s mind, however you cannot ignore the
impact of the human experience. If you are reading something not-so-genius but
you learn a valuable lesson from it, I would argue it would be a wise choice.
While Seneca&amp;rsquo;s analogy of a wound not healing if subjected to experiments of
several ointments, or a plant weakening from constant uprooting is compelling,
engaging with a multitude of viewpoints and getting perspective deepens your
understanding of things. With this in mind, I would not say reading a lot of
garbage self-help authors or a bunch of phony writers would do your life any
good. Picking the right authors is without a doubt a good first step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seneca also suggests focusing more on the quality than the quantity of books.
This resonates with my philosphy and it is something I really struggle with
sometimes. Whenever I start a book, my heart &lt;strong&gt;wants&lt;/strong&gt; to finish it (as most of
us would like to). However, this is a key point to keep in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;i&gt;To read that brings pleasure, and to let go of books that cause pain.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To use this knowledge as a shield against life&amp;rsquo;s adversities and cultivate the
habit of resilience is valuable advice. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t agree more with Seneca when
he says, &amp;ldquo;It is not the man who has too little who is poor, but the one who
hankers after more&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Letter III&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;letter-iii&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#letter-iii&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember the popular proverb, &lt;em&gt;A friend in need is a friend indeed&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this letter, Seneca addresses Lucilius&amp;rsquo;s distrust towards his friend, and
&lt;em&gt;dramatically&lt;/em&gt; questions him if he &amp;ldquo;actually&amp;rdquo; called him a friend or if it was
merely out of courtesy. This debate evokes a point in my life, when I stood by
this philosophy of &lt;em&gt;true friendship&lt;/em&gt;. (as ridiculous as it sounds) I reserved
the title of a &lt;em&gt;friend&lt;/em&gt; with those I shared a deep friendship, while others,
less intimately known, remained acquaintances. The significance of words may be
overlooked in today&amp;rsquo;s world, yet the value words hold must remain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/friends.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400px&#34;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, &lt;em&gt;Friendship&lt;/em&gt; is a bond built on trust, where we willingly place our
hearts and souls at our friend&amp;rsquo;s feet, trusting they will not deceive us.
Overcoming fear of betrayal demands reflecting the same trust we have in
ourselves. Seneca offers timeless wisdom on this matter, advising against both
indiscriminately confiding in everyone and keeping secrets from our closest
friends. Certainly judgement must precede freely sharing thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seneca believes being busy in life doesn&amp;rsquo;t always equate to productivity,
rather signifies a troubled mind. Likewise, condemning all activity leads to
laziness and not a relaxed mind. He advocates for striking a balance and
suggests looking towards nature for relaxation. Below is a quote I really found
interesting in this letter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Some men have shrunk so far into dark corners that objects in broad daylight
seem quite blurred to them&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Letter V&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;letter-v&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#letter-v&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seneca earnestly approves of those constantly learning, determined for
self-improvement. To be a better man (or woman) is essential, however he warns
against doing it to seek attention, or for solely provoking others through
appearances or ways of living. This is profoundly accurate in an era, dominated
by FAANG mania, Instagram reelz and TikTok trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is fascinating how a philosopher born centuries ago accurately describes our
reality. Better yet shares his ideas on how to lead a simple life. Maybe, this
philosophy is deeply rooted in the essence of humanity, passed down through
generations; a promise of belonging to one race, one global community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seneca puts this beautifully: &lt;i&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our motto, as one knows, is to live in
conformity with nature.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some key points I found fascinating in this letter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admiring one&amp;rsquo;s way of life, and appreciate the beauty in its simplicity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admire one&amp;rsquo;s character and values, instead of their material possessions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seneca also highlights how &lt;em&gt;fear&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;hope&lt;/em&gt; march in unison &amp;ldquo;like a prisoner
and escort he is handcuffed to&amp;rdquo;. This theme is widely explored, so I would just
like to add how memory brings back the agony of fear, and as philosophical as
it sounds, one must live in the present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Letter VI&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;letter-vi&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#letter-vi&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this letter, Seneca writes to Lucilius that he observes not only
improvement, but also transformation within himself. While humbly admitting his
imperfections, Seneca admits the significance of sharing his feelings with his
friend (as discussed in a previous letter). Additionally, he highlights the
mutual benefit of exchanging insights through shared books. Knowledge is
valuable if shared, useless if held in secret. My philosophy on this remains.
Talking to someone each day and studying their character benefits more than
conversing with someone rarely. More often than not, to be your own friend too
is a wonderful idea of progress, atleast in theory. Nonetheless to share-it-all
with a friend is a priceless benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Letter VII&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;letter-vii&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#letter-vii&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a world driven through trends, events and content, there is always a chaotic
mind. Though Seneca highlights in this letter that consorting with a mass crowd
is harmful, I beleive mingling with the wrong crowd is far more perilous. It&amp;rsquo;s
often said that one&amp;rsquo;s character is significantly influenced by the five closest
people one associates with. Therefore, it is essential to be picky in that respect.
Someone who improves your character; Someone who you can improve. A process of
mutual improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;center&gt;A few is enough for me; so is one; and so is none. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stoicism&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stoicism&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Empire of Hell</title>
      <link>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/empire-of-hell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 07:32:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unchaineddev.github.io/blog/empire-of-hell/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;All the world&amp;rsquo;s a digital stage, &lt;br&gt;
and all the men and women merely scrollin&amp;rsquo; &amp;ndash; &lt;br&gt;
with no exits, their entrance is a screen &amp;ndash; &lt;br&gt;
a portal to their unseen dreams. broken&lt;br&gt;
and broke. impulse and hope-less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a double-edged sword. swallow whole&lt;br&gt;
pleasure and pain. one man at their time&lt;br&gt;
plays many parts of ruin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His acts being seven gigs of your intimate data.&lt;br&gt;
first phase of his playbook &amp;ndash; lure you in.&lt;br&gt;
Then gather and sell, finally build networth&lt;br&gt;
and tell the world, &amp;ldquo;I created an empire of hell.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
