<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unchained Dev – Finance</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/finance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Finance on Unchained Dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 08:19:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero1 Fest 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/zero1-fest-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 08:19:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/zero1-fest-2024/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;center&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/braindump/zero1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;700px&#34;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last weekend I attended the Zero1 Fest &amp;ndash; the world’s first festival around
finance and money. It was exhilarating to be in the presence of people whose
content I deeply admire; whose profound knowledge especially in finance has
influenced and &amp;ldquo;de-influenced&amp;rdquo; me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the opportunity to see the Kamath brothers up close, whose startup serves
as a powerful reminder that a business can thrive without backing of venture
capital. I had a chat with Karthik Rangappa, curator of Varsity and expressed
deep appreciation for his captivating content. I was nostalgic to see Rob from
&amp;ldquo;M.A.D&amp;rdquo; fame, whose show was a beloved staple for 90s and early 2000s kids. I
had a brief moment with Prateek Singh, Founder &amp;amp; CEO of LearnApp and Zero1
Media, whose talk with Radhika Gupta (Edelweiss CEO) left a lasting impression.
Although I missed out on meeting many other familiar faces like Abid Hassan,
Rahul Subramanian, Nas, among others, I still had a wonderful time!&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coffee Can Investing - A Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/coffee-can-investing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 11:58:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/coffee-can-investing/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;The best time to plant a tree was twenty years ago; the second best time is now.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I strongly beleive in the eight wonder of the world. It may be common sensical
for someone with good discipline, patience, and consistency that the secret
lies in waiting for the magic to unfold. The only way, my friend is paying the
price: &lt;em&gt;Time&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This magical reminder comes in a form of a book: Coffee Can Investing by Saurab
Mukherjea and his team, that have created a roadmap that captures the common
pitfalls of a common retail investor. A guide to make wise financial decisions
without compromising on your wants and desires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would highly recommend this book to someone who wants to filter out the noise
and focus on the goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Note:&lt;/u&gt; It may not be necessary for everyone to read the entire book, yet
skimming through to understand the core philosophy should do the trick.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
